Jake Brawer

PERSONAL DATA

Ph.D.: 6th Year

Website: http://jakebrawer.com/ Email: jake.brawer@yale.edu

Github: https://github.com/JakeBrawer

Research overview

Summary

I build **human–robot collaborative systems** that learn through their interactions with people. My research draws upon recent innovations in machine learning as well as foundational techniques in artificial intelligence for designing systems that learn and reason in a **transparent** and **robust** way.

EDUCATION

2016-Current Ph.D. in Computer Science Yale University, Advisor: Brian Scassellati

2012-2016 B.A. in Cognitive Science; Computer Science minor Vassar College

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

2016-Current Robotics Ph.D. student –Social robotics laboratory, Yale University Human–robot collaboration research under the supervision of Professor Brian Scassellati.

2014-2015 **Research Fellow** –Interdisciplinary robotics research lab, *Vassar College* Designed and programmed a genotype-phenotype mapping scheme for mobile behavior-based robots incorporating sexual reproduction and ontogenetic factors.

2014 **Neuroscience researcher** –Icahn School of Medicine, *Mount Sinai* Conducted fMRI research on resting state networks in macaque monkeys. Acquired skills using fMRI analysis software FSL.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Spring Intelligent Robotics

2018/2019 Teaching Assistant

Fall 2017 Object Oriented Programming

Teaching Assistant

Fall 2014/2015 Perception and Action

Teaching Assistant

TECHNICAL AND SCIENTIFIC SKILLS

Human-robot collaboration, natural language understanding Research Programming Python (and scientific tools), C-C++, LATEX, Git, Jekyll, Emacs, Continuous integration (with Travis) ML/AIGeneral machine learning and computer vision techniques Robot operating system (ROS), 5+ years experience with Baxter research robot, Robots 2+ years experience with **UR5** robot System 8+ years of daily **Linux** experience Grants Bridging the Gap: An NSF Workshop on Conversational Agents and March 2018 **Human-Robot Interaction** Justine Cassell, Brian Scassellati, Jake Brawer, Michael Madaio NSF Cyber-Human Systems (CHS), Robust Intelligence, National Robotics Initiative. Award #1829237 SERVICE International Conference on Humanoid Robots (Humanoids; 2018) Conference reviews International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS; 2020) International Conference on Human–Robot Interaction (HRI; 2017, 2018, 2019,

Journal ACM Transactions on Human–Robot Interaction (THRI; 2019, 2020)

International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA; 2019)

reviews

Students Kevin Choi (2018)

supervised Acshi Haggenmiller (2016-2017)

2020, 2021, 2022)

Sarah Widder (2017-2019) Tan Zong Xuan (2017-2018) Kayleigh Bishop (2017-2019)

Conference proceedings

Brawer, Jake, Qin, Meiying, and Scassellati, Brian (2020). "A causal approach to tool affordance learning". In: 2020 IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS). IEEE, pp. 8394–8399. URL: https://jakebrawer.com/assets/pdfs/IROS2020.pdf.

Brawer, Jake, Mangin, Olivier, Roncone, Alessandro, Widder, Sarah, and Scassellati, Brian (2018). "Situated Human-Robot Collaboration: predicting intent from grounded natural language". In: Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS). URL: https://jakebrawer.com/assets/pdfs/IROS18.pdf.

Scassellati, Brian, **Brawer**, **Jake**, Tsui, Katherine, Nasihati Gilani, Setareh, Malzkuhn, Melissa, Manini, Barbara, Stone, Adam, Kartheiser, Geo, Merla, Arcangelo, Shapiro, Ari, et al. (2018). "**Teaching Language to Deaf Infants with a Robot and a Virtual Human**". In: *Proceedings*

- of the 2018 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. ACM, p. 553. URL: https://jakebrawer.com/assets/pdfs/CHI18.pdf.
- Tan, Zong Xuan, Brawer, Jake, and Scassellati, Brian (2018). "That's Mine! Learning Ownership Relations and Norms for Robots". In: *Thirty-second AAAI conference on artificial intelligence*. URL: https://jakebrawer.com/assets/pdfs/AAAI18.pdf.

JOURNAL ARTICLES

- *Qin, Meiying, *Brawer, Jake, and Scassellati, Brian (2021). "Rapidly Learning Generalizable and Robot-Agnostic Tool-Use Skills for a Wide Range of Tasks". In: Frontiers in Robotics and AI 8. URL: https://jakebrawer.com/assets/pdfs/CHI22.pdf.
- Brawer, Jake, Hill, Aaron, Livingston, Ken, Aaron, Eric, Bongard, Joshua, and Long Jr, John H (2017). "Epigenetic Operators and the evolution of Physically embodied robots". In: Frontiers in Robotics and AI 4, p. 1. URL: https://jakebrawer.com/assets/pdfs/FRONTIERS17.pdf.